Spectre is a action, adventure, thriller film directed by Sam Mendes.
A cryptic message from Bond’s past sends him on a
trail to uncover a sinister organization.
While M battles political forces to keep the secret service alive, Bond peels back
the layers of deceit to reveal the terrible truth behind SPECTRE.
James Bond, played by Daniel Craig.
Blofeld, played by Christoph Waltz.
Madeleine, played by Léa Seydoux.
M, played by Ralph Fiennes.
Lucia, played by Monica Bellucci.
Q, played by Ben Whishaw.
Spectre is a 2015 spy thriller film directed by Sam Mendes and written by John Logan, Neal Purvis,
Robert Wade, and Jez Butterworth from a story conceived by Logan, Purvis, and Wade.
The sequel to Skyfall (2012), it is the twenty-fourth installment in the James Bond film series produced by
Eon Productions and the fourth film to star Daniel Craig as the fictional MI6 agent James Bond.
The film co-stars Christoph Waltz, Léa Seydoux, Ben Whishaw, Naomie
Harris, Dave Bautista, Monica Bellucci, and Ralph Fiennes.
It was the last Bond film to be co-distributed by Sony Pictures Releasing.
In the film, Bond battles Spectre, an international crime
organisation led by Ernst Stavro Blofeld (Waltz).
Despite initially stating he would not direct Spectre, Mendes confirmed his return in 2014 after Nicolas Winding Refn
declined to direct; Mendes became the first to direct successive James Bond films since John Glen.
The inclusion of Spectre and its associated characters marked the end of the Thunderball controversy, in which Kevin McClory and Fleming were embroiled in
lengthy legal disputes over the film rights to the novel; Spectre is the first film to feature these elements since Diamonds Are Forever (1971).
Following the Sony Pictures hack, it was revealed Sony and Eon clashed regarding finance, stunts, and
filming locations; Spectre is estimated to have a final budget of $245–300 million.
Principal photography began in December 2014 and lasted until July 2015, with filming
locations including Austria, the United Kingdom, Italy, Morocco, and Mexico.
Spectre premiered at the Royal Albert Hall on 26 October 2015 and was theatrically released in conventional
and IMAX formats in the United Kingdom that day, and in the United States on 6 November.
The film received mixed reviews from critics, who praised the action sequences, cast performances (particularly Craig's
and Bautista's), and the musical score, but criticised the pacing and formulaic narrative decisions.
It grossed $880 million worldwide, making it the sixth-highest-grossing film of 2015 and the second-highest
grossing James Bond film after Skyfall, unadjusted for inflation (fourth when adjusted).
The film's theme song, "Writing's on the Wall", won an Academy
Award and Golden Globe for Best Original Song.
The next film in the series, No Time to Die, was released in 2021.
The film explores themes of based on novel or
book, spy, secret agent, sequel, mi6.
The tone is intense.